Most law enforcement officers are
actually afraid to go hands-on. They're
afraid to deal with people like you.
It's not a game.
>> They're not afraid to deal with us.
>> Absolutely. A lot of people are.
>> We are an officer's dream.
>> Is there corruption? Yes. Is there self-
serving people who want to promote? Yes.
But for you to Well, that's not what
you're saying.
>> No, it's not. What am I saying?
>> Where's the BS button?
>> You guys violated your oath or you would
>> We were criminals. You can't compare us
to the If you compare us to the FBI, we
were in a lot of trouble.
>> Not compared.
>> Hi, I'm Michael Francis. I'm a former
cop regime in the Columbbo family in New
York, one of the five New York mafia
families. And today I'm surrounded by 20
cops.
All right, my first surrounded claim is
undercover sting operations often
manufacture crime.
I'm not far away.
>> How do you do?
>> Nice to meet you.
>> So, you believe that undercover
operations create crime.
>> Absolutely.
>> Let's talk about the word entrapment.
So, entrapment means that law
enforcement officers are inducing a
reasonable person who is not predisposed
to a crime to commit a crime.
Well, what do you mean a reasonable
person? Not No. In my experience, the
undercover operations were either an
undercover law enforcement person or
somebody a confidential informant that
was put into that situation. That's not
a fine un upstanding person. Normally,
the undercover agent, absolutely. Okay.
>> But not that other person.
>> So, I've worked undercover. I've worked
undercover in multiple situations.
>> You're a fine upstanding person.
>> Thank you. I appreciate that. And
looking at it from that perspective, if
I was doing a prostitution sting,
walking the streets, then
if people weren't predisposed to
committing crime, they could keep
driving or keep walking right by me.
>> Correct.
>> So, the fact that I and my law
enforcement agency created an arena for
someone to make a decision does not mean
that I manufactured crime for them. I
did not force them to commit crime. They
made that final decision. I agree with
that and I believe that undercover sting
operations are necessary. Okay?
>> You know, to catch crim people that you
suspect of being criminals. However,
there are situations that I'm very
familiar with where they will use
another criminal,
>> okay, to go into that, become a
confidential informant and he will help
to manufacture a crime by getting people
to say things that they wouldn't have
ordinarily said. put them in a
situation, bring them a criminal
activity of some and put them into it.
So, yeah, because they don't know what
this other person is doing. I I give you
an example, Michael Francis. We know
he's an organized crime guy. We got our
informants told us that, but we haven't
been able to catch him in a crime. So,
let's send somebody in there and see if
they can create something to put him
involved in. And then we have our crime.
That's done.
>> It is. But sending someone in like a
confidential informant, there's also a
lot of controls that are on the law
enforcement side.
>> So whether that person is wired or
there's an infiltration of a law
enforcement officer on, you know, as
part of the act,
they're still not causing crime to be
manufactured. It's all being done
rightfully by the suspect.
>> I I I can't agree with that. I I cannot.
When you wire up a confidential
informant and that informant brings
criminal activity to that other person
because that's the person that's the
subject of the sting operation, that's
entrament as far as I'm concerned
because that wouldn't have happened if
your confidential informant didn't go in
and manufacture that crime. They're
bringing him the crime. They're creat
he's part of that criminal activity.
>> Understood. But if you didn't want to
commit that crime, you wouldn't have to.
You could walk away. You could be like,
you know what? I don't want to I don't
want to do this robbery tonight. I don't
want to put something I don't want to
put a, you know, amount of money on
someone's head. I can just walk away.
>> Absolutely. And if you do, you're not
entrapped. But if you do it, then you
are entrapped. And that's what the
confidential informant is supposed to
do. Entra you.
>> I I understand what you're saying, but
you just made my argument.
>> So if you could walk away from that, and
if you walk away from that, it's not
enttrapment. You're not getting involved
in the criminal activity where if you
stay involved in it, you were
predisposed to move forward with that
crime regardless. So, it's not
enttrapment either.
>> Well, I disagree with that. I think
because it would have never happened if
you didn't put if law enforcement didn't
put their CI in there to try to entrap
that guy, then it would have been no
crime.
>> But if the person they were trying to
entrap, let's say it's you, if you were
going in with a clean conscience, not
wanting to commit crime at all, then it
wouldn't matter who they put in there.
>> But it doesn't matter. It doesn't matter
because you're still creating the crime.
Law enforcement is creating the crime
through their confidential informant
because it would have never happened if
that confidential informant if he never
met him then there would be no crime.
>> So the confidential informant comes in
saying I want to do XYZ crime. You can
still walk away.
>> You can and then there's no enttrapment.
But there wouldn't have been anything at
all if your guy didn't come in. He
wouldn't have had to refuse anything
because there wouldn't have been
anything.
>> So you're saying you're saying you would
never have committed a crime no matter
what it was if there wasn't a
confidential informant that came in.
>> I'm not No. If but here's what I'm
saying. can then get him for that crime.
Then the government didn't push that.
The government didn't create it. The
government didn't manufacture it. He did
it on his own. You have every right to
get him at that point.
>> The government provided an opportunity
and the person can decide whether or not
to take that opportunity.
>> That's correct. That's correct. But let
me ask you a question. There's somebody
here's somebody here who just uh he's
broke. He's got no money. No money at
all. Never committed a crime in his
life. Innocent guy. Okay. Can't put food
on his table. You don't like that guy.
You know what? I don't like him. I don't
know what to do. He's not a criminal.
But I'm gonna send somebody in there and
give him some incentive. I'm gonna send
somebody in there to talk to this guy to
tell him, "Listen, I have this jewelry
store that we can rob. Don't worry about
it. Inside job, nobody's going to know
anything. Okay, but come with me. We'll
do it. Now you can put food on the
table." So, you created a crime. You
manufactured a crime for a guy that
never was in trouble in his life.
>> He may never have been trouble in his
life, but if he wasn't already thinking
that he could get away with that crime
or commit that crime, he would say no.
You can't get you can't get a you can't
lock somebody up for their what they
think. I may think of committing. I may
want want to rob Brinks truck, but I'm
not going to do it.
>> Of course.
>> So So you can't you can't get mad at me
for what I'm thinking.
>> But if he doesn't move forward with
robbing that jewelry store, then there's
no
>> understand you didn't understand what I
said. You didn't like that guy. He
wasn't a criminal. You just didn't like
him.
>> Yeah.
>> But I I can't do anything about it. But
I'm law enforcement. I have a tool. I
have a weapon. I have a CI. I'm going to
send him in there. I'm gonna bait this
guy into committing a crime.
>> I love that you think there's enough
time and staff to be able to screw
people over
>> in the world of organized crime. Okay,
they got all the money, all the
resources. Let me tell you something.
During my time in organized crime, we
had 750 made guys that comprised all
five families. We had 1,400 agents, two
agents to every one guy. They had plenty
of time. That's what they get paid for.
They have plenty of time and they put a
lot of effort into it and they put a lot
of guys. They destroyed my former life.
They have all the time in the world when
they want to. I'm not saying you do or
anybody else in this room. I'm telling
you my experience. And let me tell you
something. I had a lot more respect at
that time for uh police. They were doing
their job. I understand that. People say
to me, Michael, now you know, you got to
hate the police. I said, "No, I don't
hate the police. I have a wife. I have
five daughters. I have grandkids. When
they walk down the street, I want the
police to protect them. I support the
police, but I don't support the
underhanded stuff that was done and that
continues to be done. I'm sorry. I think
the defund the police movement is the
most ridiculous thing I've ever heard.
I'm totally against that. But I'm
totally against law enforcement using
tactics and weapons to get people that
they shouldn't be doing. They have to
play by the rules. Period. Or we have
anarchy.
>> You're right. And they do play by the
rules because providing a criminal
opportunity does not force someone to
commit a crime. And if that person is
getting lured into the crime because
they don't have enough uh mental
fortitude to say no to something, that's
not law enforcement.
>> Lock somebody up for their mentality.
>> But they're if they move forward,
>> they have to commit the crime.
>> If and if the confidential informant
gets them to move forward and commit the
crime,
>> well, did they manufacture that crime
then? Yes or no?
>> Absolutely not.
There was no crime until law enforcement
put the guy there to make the crime.
>> And the person they wanted to arrest
could have said no.
>> I understand. But there would have been
nothing to say no to if the government
didn't put that crime in front of them.
So they manufactured it. There was no
crime before that.
>> Okay. Pause. You've been voted out by
the majority. Please return to your
seats.
>> You are. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
>> What took you guys? Yeah. [laughter]
Adam, how are you? Nice to meet you.
>> We're both New York guys. We're adults,
right? We make our own decisions.
Correct.
>> Now, I'm going to go out on a limb and
say 99.999%
of undercover stings aren't just us
being like, John Doe, you want to show
off shotgun. You know what I'm saying?
Like, it's not how it is.
>> I agree.
>> We already probably have dirt on you in
some facet, right?
>> Well, you think you do. Yeah.
>> Either way, sure. Fair. All right. Fair.
Fine. So, we're going to set up a 20man
team, audio, video, all this stuff just
for a random dude.
>> No.
>> Right. [laughter] Yeah,
>> that's my point.
>> No, let No, but what's the difference?
Let's say let's put out a name that
everybody knows. Let's say it's John
Gotti.
>> We know that John Gotti is the boss of
the Gambino family. We'd love to see him
in jail,
>> okay?
>> But we don't know what he's doing at
this point. So, we have to figure it
out.
>> So, let's get a confidential informant,
okay? wire him up or do whatever it is
that you do and put him with John Gotti
and try to bait John Gotti into doing
something, whatever it might be, so that
we can get something on him. Tell me
you're not manufacturing that.
>> He's still in the crime family. He's
still running them up. Like it doesn't
matter.
>> Being in the crime family is is not a
crime.
>> Sure.
>> Yes, I understand that. No, for sure.
Yeah. But if you still put a CI in the
room with him, he's like, "Hey boss, you
want to commit murder today?" He's going
to be like, "Actually, no. We're going
to pass on that." Like, no, he's still
going to do the crimes he's doing. Now,
we just have an inside guy to wire that
up.
>> But you don't know that.
>> You don't know that.
>> That's the point of the undercover
sting.
>> Exactly. But you're manufacturing that
particular crime. You are creating if
he's the So, so some So, no one's going
to tell the boss of the crime or the
crime to say what he's going to do.
>> You don't You're not understanding.
There still was no crime. You're
creating a particular crime by bringing
that confidential informant into him and
giving him a situation, a criminal
situation that you're hoping he bites
into. If there was no confidential
informant, there's no crime. So, you
manufactured that
>> making him do anything. He could he
could easily be like, "We're not doing
that today."
>> He can he can say no. But I'm going to
say the same thing that I said to that
young lady. He wouldn't have to say no
if you didn't manufacture something for
him to say no.
>> He doesn't say yes. This is like this is
a a circle.
>> It doesn't matter. [laughter] No, no,
because we're the question is
>> do confidential informants manufacture
crimes? The answer is yes. You're just
agreeing with me because yes, he's
bringing a criminal situation to John
Gotti that didn't exist before. If
another criminal came to me and said,
"Michael, let's do this crime together
and I did it." Okay, I did it. But if
the government sent that guy in there,
then the government is manufacturing.
>> You still have free will and you could
be like, "No,
>> but it doesn't matter."
>> You're right. But the there would be no
crime if the government didn't make that
happen. You're bringing that crime to
saying yes. And again, we would already
have something on you or think we have
something on you. You're not sure. No,
for sure. You're not a random person is
my point.
>> Doesn't matter if you're random or not.
Everybody has the same rights.
>> Yeah. If you're a if if you're alleged
to be a criminal, but you didn't commit
a crime, you still have rights as a as
an American citizen. So, it doesn't
matter what you think, doesn't matter.
What you suppose doesn't matter. You
could say, "Yeah, John Gotti is doing a
million different things. We don't know
what they are, but let's get somebody to
do something so that we do know what it
is. You're manufacturing that crime. It
didn't exist before." Now, you've been
voted. All right. Nice meeting you,
fellow New Yorker. Thank you.
Hi,
>> how are you?
>> I'm well. How are you?
>> Good.
>> I love that you brought up the Gambino
family. Uh, one because there was more
to it than I guess was just discussed
before, right? So, we talk about Joey V.
Joey's the one who who took them down.
He was pulled over and he was in
possession of a large amount of cocaine,
right? So, he that's how he was located.
And then I think the word that you're
using manufacturing, I kind of
understand where you're coming from.
You're saying that we're being a part of
something that is criminal, so therefore
we're helping to manufacture it. When in
reality, what it is is we're going in
there. And so we talk about um one of
the captains of the Gambino family who
had a construction company,
racketeering, fraud, all of those
things, you know, tax evasion, all the
things. So when we're sending in an
informant, we're looking for those
things. We're not necessarily committing
a crime also alongside the people who
are already engaged in criminal
activity.
>> No, you're not committing the crime, but
you're manufacturing the crime.
>> But if we're finding evidence by
utilizing an undercover uh detective or
a corroborating witness, we're not
engaging in criminal activity. We're
locating criminal activity that's
already in place. or by bringing that
confidential informant in, you
manufacturing it as far as I'm concerned
because it didn't it wasn't there before
this particular informant brought it to
the alleged defendant or perpetrator.
Let's put it that way.
>> Okay. So, let let's use your example.
>> Okay.
>> I I pull somebody over and we're going
to go into narcotics. We we're not even
going to necessarily talk about
organized crime in a mafia family, but I
pull over somebody and I pull them over
and they're like, "Man, I can't go to
jail again. I can't go to jail." and we
know that they're a lower level uh you
know holder or maybe even a seller and
we want the the big person there's
already a relationship there where
criminal activity is already occurring
otherwise we're not getting someone in
the door right so if I pulled somebody
over from your family or your ex family
and I
>> I was a Columbbo guy by the way
>> but I was very familiar with the Gambino
>> no I know I'm pretty familiar with the
Gambino family I'm a Jersey girl by the
way um but
>> I could tell
>> so hell yeah so what I'm saying is if
I'm building a a corroborating witness
or a confidential informant and I
utilize that person into an
investigation, there's already a
relationship there based on the criminal
activity that's happened. There's
already things that they're bringing to
the table to make sure that I understand
their why as whether or not I can even
use them, right? Reliable or not.
Nobody's reliable fully. So, I need
other things to show me that I'm going
to be able to have the evidence to move
forward. So, I'm not always asking
somebody to commit a crime with somebody
in order to be a part of a manufacturing
or whatever crime. I'm looking for the
evidence. Whether it's going in there
and it's it's looking at your books or
sitting in on a dinner where there's
conversations being had that can
corroborate the information that we
believe we already have. It's not going
to be like, "Hey, I know, you know," and
you used Gotti as the example. So, I
know that Gotti is the the boss. Uh I'm
not going to like just manufacture
something. I'm going to I'm going to
start doing surveillance. I'm going to
I'm going to watch criminal activity
take place. I'm going to utilize that to
build probable cause.
>> Yeah. you you're bringing together the
totality of the of the tools that you
have, the weapons that you have uh to
investigate this crime.
>> Correct.
>> Nothing wrong with that. I get it. I
mean,
>> but that's what a CI or or an undercover
is going to help me do as well.
>> It's after those things that I just
talked to you about are starting to form
or at least that's how an investigation
goes in Jersey that I've been a part of.
We're utilizing all those things to come
together and then use that CI to go in
and witness criminal activity that's
already taking place in a criminal
environment. It's not something we're
already manufacturing.
>> Let me give you an example. I was a
subject of an undercover operation. It
was me and Don King.
>> Okay?
>> The government was trying to allege and
prove that uh organized crime was
involved in professional boxing. So they
had an undercover informant and an FBI
agent that went on, you know,
undercover. And they were with me for
eight or nine months. Now, I was not
involved in this organized crime, being
involved in in professional boxing, but
I was a target. They believe that they
can get to me to try to prove their
case. It never happened. I was never
involved in it. But for eight months,
they tried to get me involved in
criminal activity and infiltrate me and
Don King. They tried to get me to get
Don King to take a bribe and all this
kind of stuff. It we didn't go for it
and the investigation went down. If they
would have got me to go along with it,
they manufactured it.
>> They were trying to look to get you to
fit the crime that they wanted because
they couldn't get you somewhere else.
Correct. I can understand where your
point is coming from. We're saying that
we're manufacturing the crime by by
bringing you in and building that
relationship. But again, to go back, you
still say yes or no to it. We're giving
you the opportunity to say yes or no.
And you're saying you said no.
>> Yeah. But but but I would have had
nothing to say no to if the government
didn't try to trap me into it. They
actually tried to lay a trap for me to
get involved.
>> And they didn't. So you're saying the
criminal justice system worked for you?
>> I guess
>> because that's what it is, right? It's a
it's a justice system for criminals. You
could say I got lucky. I got whatever. I
didn't bite, you know. But I almost did.
I'm going to be honest with you. I'm not
that brilliant. I almost did, but I
didn't. But I would have had nothing to
say no to if they didn't manufacture the
crime. Okay.
>> Pause. We're out of time.
>> Okay.
>> If you understand my point.
>> I do. I do. I don't agree, but I
understand.
>> That's okay. You understand? [laughter]
>> Thank you. My next surrounding claim is
that law enforcement believes it's okay
to violate the law in order to arrest
the law breakers.
>> [music]
>> Hey Michael, nice. How are you? Nice to
meet you.
Michael,
>> I want to start with a uh with a
question. How many cases as a law
enforcement officer have you worked?
>> Have I worked as a law enforcement? Yes.
None.
>> Okay. My point is you don't know the ins
and outs from our perspective of how
much work time away from our family
effort to get a good case that's going
to stick. You think we want to mess all
that work up by breaking the law? I
mean, you would understand that that
that would seem very foolish, right?
>> No. Not if your name is John Gotti,
Sunny Francis, Michael Francis, Fat Tony
Solerno, Joe Columbo. No, I don't think
that's unreasonable that law enforcement
would break the law in order to catch
somebody that they think is is a name
like that. I've seen it happen. And
>> in what ways have you seen it happen?
>> By sub by suborning perjury. by holding
back exculpatory material at a trial, by
FBI agents coercing people into uh uh
testifying, coercing people into going
undercover against people. I've seen
that my whole life.
>> And listen, I mean, we can't speak on
definites, right? Like I've always
taught my kids, anything that you any
sentence that you start with like
everyone, all nobody, never. The next
thing you say is going to be a lie.
Okay? So, are there cops that have
broken the law jeopardizing cases that
they have worked very, very hard for? Of
course.
>> Thank you.
>> But
>> you you just made my point.
>> No, I know. But but but it's not it's
not definite, right? And I would say the
the vast majority the vast majority of
police officers,
>> they're not doing that because of the
amount the amount of work. But of of
course we can agree that it does happen.
There's too many there's too many
people, too many variables for to say it
never happens. I don't think that's the
claim. The claim makes it seem more like
it happens more than it does not happen.
And that's just absolutely wrong. I
think it depends upon who the targets
are. Certain law enforcement people
build their careers on the names of
people that they go after. Certainly
with John Gotti, certainly with my dad,
Stony Frances, to me, with me to a
certain extent.
>> You have to admit that big names give
people in law enforcement an incentive
to work a little bit harder to bring
them down because you get rewarded for
that
>> because what comes with those big names?
>> A reward if you convict
>> many victims, right? A reward if you
convict them. Yes or no?
>> A reward if you can victim. A reward for
a job well done for anybody. But but but
big names equal many victims. I think
that's the point that that we're missing
here
>> because a local street dealer, you know,
may affect 20, 30, 50, 100 lives, right?
But a John Gotti is affecting hundreds.
Would John Gotti affect the same amount
of people uh and you know, same amount
of victims as the lower level guy in the
family? Probably not, right? Like
there's a reason why John Gotti became
the boss, right? Let me tell you
something. Most of the time, the
informants that are going against the
big guys, they're the ones that are
doing most of the crime,
>> right? I think to stick to the the point
at hand to say that nobody no no police
officer has ever broken the law
jeopardizing their case, that would be
foolish. I would never say that, right?
Because again, there's too many
variables. But the way that the claim
states makes it seem almost like it's
common practice. It's just not true.
>> Let me make it clear right now. I hope
to believe that most law enforcement
people are on the level. I have many
friends in law enforcement now. The guy
that was trying to put me away forever
on that undercover sting operation
became one of my best friends now. He's
back in New York, Joe Spanelli. He was
the head of the FBI. Good guy.
>> There's a mutual respect there. That
>> mutual respect. Yes. He came after me.
Did it the right way. Listen, we told
people all the time, FBI agents, you
come and get me, get me. Just don't
frame me and don't harass my family.
That's it. Because we're not going to do
that to you. Don't do it to us. So, I
believe I want to believe that most
people in law enforcement are straight
up and they do their job. Yes. But come
on, you said it, you know it. There's
many times depending upon who that
person is that they will violate the law
or they will stretch because it puts,
you know, a feather in their cap, they
get promoted, whatever. And I know so
many people, they convict this guy, they
become a federal judge the next day.
Come on, it happens. Not all the time,
but absolutely it does.
>> Pause. You've been voted out. Thank you.
>> Y Okay.
Tom, how are you?
>> Well, you've told us a little bit about
yourself. I'll tell you a little bit
about me. I spent 23 years as an FBI
agent, all in Los Angeles, so I have no
personal experience of working in New
York as an agent and I never worked
organized crime.
>> You know Scott Garola?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Very well. Good friend.
>> Yeah. Oh, very good. I was married to a
cop for many years, LAPD. I've known
hundreds of police officers and worked
with hundreds and agents. And your
general statement is that law
enforcement believes, it's a pretty
broad statement, that it's okay to break
the law to get the law breaker. And I
disagree with that. You're describing an
FBI that I don't recognize. I'm I'm not
going to argue with your experience, but
in the bureau,
>> have you been paying attention to the
FBI today?
>> I have been.
>> Okay. Do you do will you agree that
they've been breaking the law?
>> No.
>> You you won't agree to that. Today's
Well, today I'm going to
>> The FBI of the last administration has
not been breaking the law, doing things
that they shouldn't be doing.
>> No, I I disagree with you vehemently on
that. The last the the Biden
administration FBI you say has been
totally above board. Comey has been
totally above board.
>> I am not going to go into some broad
political
>> I'm not being broad. I'm being factual.
You you believe that James Comey has not
broken the law. Has not been You think
he's been an honest and upright and
law-abiding FBI agent?
>> I think James Comey was a good director
of the FBI while he was the director. I
think he operated with integrity and
honor.
>> We disagree. And he was widely respected
while he was director. Do I think he may
have made some mistakes of judgment
along the way? Yes, I could say that.
>> Why did Why did he allow Hillary Clinton
to smash her her No, excuse me. I would
have went to jail for that and so would
everybody in this room. Why would Why
would he allow Hillary Clinton to smash
all of her uh uh computers and
everything that she had information on
and not indict her for obstruction of
justice?
My understanding of that case is that
she was not entitled because they could
not prove a criminal intent. Now,
earlier today,
>> she admitted they she admitted that uh
they whitewashed her computers and
everything else. All the information
that she had in there, she broke her
phones and everything else. She admitted
to it. She did it.
>> Your argument earlier is that law
enforcement will break the law to break
lawb breaker to catch lawb breakakers.
>> That's not my experience. My experience
of the FBI is for every investigative
technique I had to uh get approval at
every step of the way. Let's take a
trash cover. For the audience, a trash
cover is when law enforcement picks up
the trash that somebody puts out on the
street. I don't need a search warrant
for that. But the FBI requires that I
get approval from my supervisor in
writing and articulate why I'm going to
conduct this operation, what's the
purpose of it, and then I have to
document the results.
>> Have you Are you familiar with a with an
FBI agent named Lind Devio?
>> No.
>> Okay. He he was indicted for murder.
More for murders because he worked
>> I think more of your guys than my guys
have been indicted for murder.
>> Absolutely. Because we were criminals,
but the FBI is supposed to be upstanding
citizens that took an oath to to to
protect people. But we were criminals.
I'll admit to that. We didn't take an
oath to uh to abide by the law at all.
But FBI agents do. And I'm not saying I
want to make it clear. I'm not saying
this. I'm not throwing a blanket away
everybody. Of course you are. No, I'm
not. There are a lot of good
>> You just make a broad statement that the
FBI committed crimes during the Biden
administration. That Comey committed
crimes.
>> James Comey did. James Comey did. 100%
he did. James Comey absolutely did. I
don't throw a blanket over everybody.
Absolutely not. But there were certain
FBI agents that did not uphold the law.
>> I get that. Now, let's wind this back.
That's all I needed to hear. you have a
certain view of the Comey uh years and
that period. You're entitled to your
opinion. I'm not going to argue that
with you.
>> What I am here to tell you as from my
perspective, from my personal experience
as an agent, that we want to get the bad
guy, yes, but we don't think it's okay
to break the law and do bad things to do
it. Now, can there be a problem?
Absolutely. I know of cases where
officers and agents and or to use an
example of the FBI, uh we had a
situation where someone in the lab um
was maybe shading his his uh or her
analysis to favor the prosecution. Allow
me to finish. I listen to you very
patiently. So there is absolutely a risk
that anyone in law enforcement
could
lose sight of their ethics and their
values. And that is very much the
responsibility of the agency and the
leadership and the management to create
the culture
>> that says no to go to one of the points
you made earlier. Hey, you you don't
mind getting caught if you're caught
when law enforcement plays by the rules.
What I'm trying to tell you is that as
an agent, your friend Scott Guerola,
>> great guy.
>> Great guy. He played by the rules. The
agents that I have worked with played by
the rules. Do we make mistakes? Yes. Are
there mistakes of judgment? Allow me to
finish. Yes.
>> I I understand where you're going, but I
have a very important question. Are you
can you sit there and tell me that you
have 100% belief that no agent will
violate the law or do something
unscrupulous to catch a lawb breaker?
>> I that would be an absurd statement to
to to make.
>> I'm asking you a question. You're saying
that in your experience, no a every
agent that takes that oath abides by the
oath 100%. I am telling you is that the
FBI like any other organization every
law enfor your organization you guys
violated your oath or you wouldn't be
here right [clears throat] you can't we
were criminals you can't compare if you
compare us to the FBI
>> I'm not comparing I'm not comparing what
I'm talking about is human nature are
there human beings that are imperfect of
course they are no great debating point
to say stop it's no great debating point
to say oh you guys you had this guy who
did this of course
>> that's not the question. I asked you a
simple question. Do you believe that
every FBI agent in the bureau does
things 100% ethically all the time and
they will not stretch it in order to
catch a perpetrator? Yes or no? Yes or
no?
>> That is that is what uh uh the way that
question is framed.
>> It's yes or no.
>> It is.
>> There's no way anybody could answer, oh,
I believe every agent is perfect.
>> Why not? I can tell you people in my
organization that violated certain
things, they did it that they didn't do
it. And I'll tell you if you ask me that
question,
>> what I can speak to, what I can speak to
is what I was taught in the academy. I
can speak to the standards my
supervisors held me to. I can speak to
how my management behaved. I can speak
to the attitude of the agents I worked
with. In theory, are there I have known.
>> You've never heard of any agent that
violated their ethical uh
>> course I have. I work for one.
>> Well, that's it. I had a supervisor who
had an improper relationship with an
informant and it caused a lot of damage.
Okay. So to say that is to say wow we
have to hire human beings for this job.
>> No kidding.
>> It it's just what I said. There are
certain agencies violate their ethics to
catch the law. thing that I want you to
listen to as I've listened to you and I
want the audience to hear is that the
organization that I work for which is
made up of thousands of human beings who
have all the the flaws of every every
person but the organizational culture
that I was raised in that I served
put a premium on integrity and doing the
right thing. Are there agents that I
believe are there agents? I believe you
and I think that you're sincere in that
regard. But can I ask you a question?
Why is it that everyone all of America
practically has no trust in the FBI
right now? No. No trust in our
government agencies.
>> Many people have lied to Americans about
the FBI and about its actions and have
mischaracterized the FBI.
>> They have mischaracterized there's a
different not people lying. They've
observed the FBI. Let me tell you now, I
I I like Cash Patel and Dan Bonino. I
know him. Very ethical, good guy with
integrity. I'm so happy that he's the
the the deputy director of the FBI
because he has integrity. I can't say
that for the last people. And all of
America, a good portion of America
believes the same thing because of their
actions.
>> Actually, I think it's because they're
being lied to frequently by figures in
the media.
>> By who?
>> Well, you're doing it right now.
>> I'm not lying. No, I'm not lying, sir.
I'm telling you the truth based upon my
experience.
>> What do you know about the Clinton case?
You've recited a bunch of factually
incorrect statements.
>> Incorrect. Tell me how I'm wrong. Tell
Tell me how I'm wrong about Hillary
Clinton.
>> You're representing that somehow the FBI
knew that she'd obstructed justice. If
we could have if we could have proven a
criminal intent, an intent to violate
the law, she would have been charged.
>> You're meaning to tell me that in
>> It's the same reason why other people
aren't. You mean to tell me in the Biden
administration, they would have went
after Hillary Clinton? Biden would have
allowed the FBI and Comey would have
went after Hillary Clinton.
>> You have a belief about the the FBI and
the Department of Justice that somehow
the Biden administration was dictating
to the FBI what to do. That's not
>> theure
the bureau became too political on a
national level. I'm I'm not on a local
level. Maybe not here in LA.
>> I disagree with that. I I believe that
that has been alleged repeatedly till
it's an urban legend that people
>> see it. The FBI has been politicized
during the Biden administration. I wish
they weren't. Comey was totally
politicized. Absolutely. What they did
to Look, let me tell you this. I'm not,
you know, Donald Trump, I think he's a
good president and I want him there
because the last one would have been a
disaster. America would have been I
don't know where we would have been
right now. But but I'll tell you right
now, okay, there's no question that
Comey was politicized to do what they
did to that man.
>> To do what they did to Trump.
>> Come on.
>> I disagree with you.
>> Really?
>> I do.
>> Okay, pause.
>> Okay, you got it.
>> Turn back to your seat.
>> We're actually going to add five more
minutes to the clock for this. This is a
really good claim. We're going to add
five minutes. Not for you, Tom.
[laughter]
Thank God.
Nice to meet you. How do you meet? I'm
good.
>> So, let me ask you this. What got Gotti
got?
>> What got him got?
>> Well, the main I mean, you want to go to
the main witness against Gotti? Who was
Sammy Gvano?
>> What got him got, though?
>> Clarify
>> the mouth.
>> Oh, the mouth. Oh, no doubt about it. I
absolutely agree with that.
>> The wire, right?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. So in order to get that wire, you
know, it's certain steps we have to go
through.
>> Yes.
>> Right. A judge has to sign off on that.
Right. So you have to have all this
stuff in place before you even attempt,
>> okay,
>> to go in that house before you attempt
to climb up that pole, before you
attempt to go and put anform
confidential informant in there. Most of
that stuff has to be laid out. And a
good judge is not going to sign any of
that. He's going to look at that and
say, "What has this CI done?"
>> And what do a bad judge do? He'll just
sign it, right? Because
So you have good bad judges,
>> right? But most of the time there's a
there's a big trail. There's smoke.
There's fire, right? 90% of the time. So
what got him in trouble was he couldn't
shut up.
>> That's true.
>> Right. And that's what gets most of
crown bosses in trouble.
>> Well, not the chin.
Okay. [laughter] H how do you how did he
go down?
>> Huh?
>> How did he go down?
>> Me?
>> Yeah. How'd you go down?
>> Never on a wire, too.
>> Never on a wire? No.
>> Okay. So, your mind, how did you go
down?
>> How did I go down?
>> Can you say that informant?
>> Okay. Well, was this informant? Did he
face you in court?
>> One time he did and I was acquitted.
Yeah.
>> Okay. He testified.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. So, how did you get
acquitted? What did they what did they
say the informant didn't or didn't
provide?
>> Well, he lied. That's my point from
before. So your your attorney got got
you off, right?
>> He didn't get me off. I was innocent. So
he lied.
>> What did he lie? But what did he lie
about? What he lied about the facts that
they were trying to prove against me
that were ridiculous and the jury saw
through it and I got to quit it. Again,
I'm not throwing a blanket over every
person in law enforcement, but what I'm
saying is in certain situations, I
believe law enforcement thinks it's okay
to violate the law to catch a lawb
breakaker because well, you know, we
can't get him for what he didn't do. So,
let's try to manufacture something or
get him something that we can pin on
him. Well,
>> you think manufactur
you've been voted out by the majority.
Okay.
How are you? Good. How are you?
>> Do you believe it's possible to operate
in law enforcement without breaking any
laws?
>> I would hope so.
>> Okay. All right. So, uh, take this
situation for example. Say we get a we
get an amber Amber Alert put across for
a car that has a a kidnapped young girl
in it. Correct. A police officer is
going down the street and he sees this
car. Correct. Is that breaking the law
if you run through a red light?
>> Yes. Okay. So, the police officer should
stop at the red light while that car
drives off with the kid.
>> Absolutely not.
>> Okay. So, you're telling me that you
would hope that law enforcement can
operate without breaking any laws. But
you're telling me now that he should
break that law to go get that girl.
>> Law enforcement. I've seen law
enforcement. Are you allowed to go
through a red light as a law
enforcement?
>> Yes, you are. If you cut your lights
off, go to red light. Okay.
>> So, I think you're not breaking the law.
>> It's It's still a law in my opinion. And
I think law but you're not breaking the
law cuz you're allowed to go through a
red light. So you're not breaking the
law.
>> Okay. So we're we're we're setting the
laws out
laws then because you're saying laws in
general because
>> that would still be a law just like
speeding is a law.
>> What I'm saying is that law enforcement
in most cases now I'm to tell you
something. My daughter in a car I don't
care what law you broke. I don't care
what you did to get to her because it's
personal. Obviously it's personal. Okay.
So I understand that and I would hope
that you would do that.
>> Okay. But that's a different case. What
I'm saying is I believe that many in law
enforcement and again it always depends
upon the situation. Think it's okay.
This is a bad guy. We can't get him for
what we did. So we can manufacture or
bring something around him so that we
can put him in jail. And I think law
enforcement does that. I don't even know
if I in some cases I disagree with it.
If I knew that the guy was a serial
killer and I can't get the guy and I had
to do something to make him make a
mistake so I can I probably I would
definitely do it,
>> right?
>> But I'm a criminal at times. Not
anymore, but I was back then. [laughter]
Okay. I would definitely do it.
>> You're not supposed to do that,
>> but I wouldn't be mad if you did. Now,
let let me just ask you a question.
Let's let's be totally honest. Okay.
>> Do you believe that in some situations
it's okay for law enforcement to break
the law in order to go after lawb
breakakers? Law enforcement should be
able to break laws in a controlled
environment to to do things that other
people can't. That's the whole reason
we're there. Just like running the red
light, just like catching somebody going
100 miles an hour over the speed limit.
Cuz you were speaking specifically on
just entrament and setting people up
with stings.
>> But see, my point in that is that you're
not breaking the law if you're legally
allowed to do it. That's then you're not
a lawb breaker. You're allowed to go
past the red light. You're allowed to
speed.
>> There's a reason pause. We're out of
time.
>> Okay.
>> And I agree with that, by the way. You
should be allowed to do that.
>> Thank you.
>> My next surrounded claim is that law
enforcement often measures success by
arrests and not by safer streets.
>> How are you? How you doing, sir?
>> Good.
>> So, I'm from Houston, Texas. I'm big on,
you know, DWI DR. So, most of the time I
don't answer calls at all. my work is
driven off of stats arrest.
>> So for you to make that kind of claim is
very, you know, misleading and dangerous
because most of the time I'm put my life
at risk to stop impaired drivers, drunk
drivers. So which means if I see
somebody driving, you know, wrong way,
I'm probably going to put myself in
harm's way to, you know, stop that
driver so that somebody doesn't get hit
or killed. So I don't believe in your
claim. Do you have any any experience in
that
>> at all?
>> Well, again, you know, my experience
comes from a different place, you know,
being in the world of organized crime,
growing up in that, being a subject of
uh of several arrests and and
investigations and watching others also.
In that world, there's no question that
people uh you know, not safer streets
that they're concerned about. They're
concerned about the arrest and uh and
what it brings to them personally. So
would you say would you say making
arrest with your own organized crime is
different from me making arrests from
DWI? So so so what makes that difference
if we're still making arrest on bad
guys? It's just different crimes.
>> Well, again, you know, it goes back to
the totality of this situation. You're
not manufacturing a crime. You're not
targeting. You know, let me tell you the
difference with organized crime. Okay?
You you just pointed it out. You go
after the lawb breaker because you're
watching them violate the law. drunken
driver or whatever, right? Okay. So, you
go after the person that's committing
the crime, but a crime has been
committed. In organized crime, they go
after the person and hope that they
commit a crime or wait for them to
commit a crime because they think that
they're a lawb breaker. You're not
watching this guy for a few months
thinking he might be a drunk driver and
then waiting for him to get in a car
drunk. Right. You're not doing that.
>> That's not what I'm doing.
>> No, he's drunk driving and you're going
after him.
>> Correct. Cuz he's committing a crime at
that moment.
>> That's okay. That's what you're supposed
to do. It's a different investigation.
>> Okay. Pause. You can vote it out. I'm
sorry.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
[music]
>> How you doing?
>> How are you? Good.
>> Good. I completely disagree with you. I
think most people that go into law
enforcement, federal, state, local, are
good, decent, honorable people.
>> We agree.
>> Who put their life on the line every
single day for the American people in
this country. I don't think that people
are focused on stats, quotas, arrests.
you name it. I hear that you keep
mentioning this point about people
getting promoted because of the amount
of arrests that they make. I doubt that
happens now in modern day law
enforcement. When I first started on the
streets, I was making $15 an hour. It
didn't matter to me about how many
arrests I made. It was about whether or
not I made it home safe at night. So,
based on the premise that you just
mentioned, I completely disagree with
you 100%.
>> And I agree in part on what you said
that most people come into law
enforcement to do the right thing. But
what level of law enforcement are you
involved in? I was in county level law
enforcement.
>> In a county level, meaning that who are
the perpetrators of crimes that you
usually go after?
>> Could be anybody.
>> Could be anybody. Anybody. Okay.
>> You should be in a different world. You
should be in a world where they're going
after highle people. You mean to tell me
that highle people being arrested,
charged, convicted, bigname people uh
don't mean anything to the people that
um arrest and convict them. I've
arrested bigname people, but I think a
lot of times when I think the level that
you're trying to speak at, you're trying
to speak at a federal level, right? That
that's what I assume you're saying like
the highame cases, the big drug lords
and those type of arrests. But these
people didn't plant those guys to go
make an arrest just based on their name.
They had probable cause. They had a
reason to go after these people. Even
when you make those type of arrests, it
don't automatically equate to a
promotion or some type of accolade.
>> Not automatically, but in often cases,
it does.
>> Not not automatically. I I disagree with
that as well. I think again my premise
is that 90% of law enforcement officers
across the board don't go into
profession to make arrests. They don't
have the res resources or the time to
sit there and count how many arrests
that they're making.
>> You know who do you know who John
Gleason was? A federal prosecutor.
>> I'm I'm not familiar with him.
>> He prosecuted John Gotti. Got a
conviction. What happened to him?
>> You love John Gotti, don't you?
>> No. Everybody knows him, so you may as
well talk about him. I I can talk about
a lot of guys, but he prosecuted John
Gotti and convicted him. What happened
to him after that?
>> I don't know. But let's get back to the
>> appointed a federal judge.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Right. Right after that. You think
he didn't know that? You think he wasn't
promised that? You think that he Come
on. You have to admit that when you get
these highlevel prosecutions and
convictions that it's a feather in your
cap and you're looking for a promotion
and many times it happens.
>> I disagree. Again, I think most people
are out there doing their job and
putting their life on the line. You
can't get people to even get into law
enforcement nowadays. It is absolutely
squeezed dry. People don't want to go
into the career of law enforcement
anymore. If they do, they're going to
get a big promotion.
>> No, you know, now you're right because
the way leadership treats law
enforcement today, they should be
ashamed of themselves.
>> Well, it's the criminals. It's people
that were doing stuff like you you were
doing that drains the resources of law
enforcement. Absolutely.
>> You know, it's these woke woke leaders
that don't give a damn about the police
and that's why the police are leaving
because they don't stand behind him.
Because you arrest a criminal in New
York, you've been arrested 18 times and
the next morning you're out on no bail.
I get arrested for a for a money crime
and I'm in there with a million-doll
bail and a no bail at all. So that's why
the cops are I understand that if I was
a who would want to be a cop right now.
You're arresting criminals 20 times. You
got people committing crimes 18 times
and getting out on jail and going
murdering somebody. It's not you. It's
not the It's not the cops. I don't blame
the cops for not wanting to be there
anymore because these woke leadership
are destroying our police departments.
>> You would be Let's get back to the
premise because I actually agree with a
lot of things that you said, but you
actually proved my point that when when
police officers or law enforcement
agents are making arrest, these people
are doing it not for the accolades, not
for the glory, because there's not much
in it. Unless you're at the federal
level and you got decades of experience
in it, making a six-f figure check. So
again, your premise uh saying that we
are looking for accolades or or trying
to make arrests to get promotions is
completely false is wrong. It is. It's
absolutely false. Most of these local
guys that are working these roads,
working these streets, they have the
[clears throat] we we each and every day
we go out there, we put our life on the
line. I didn't go out there for quotas
or to make a amount of DWI arrest. In
fact, most law enforcement officers are
actually afraid to go hands-on. They're
afraid to apprehend subject. They're
afraid to deal with people like you.
It's not a game. This is not This is not
funny.
>> They're not afraid to deal with us.
>> Absolutely. A lot of people are
>> afraid to us. We We are Let me tell you
something. We are an officer's dream.
>> You arrest us, we put our hands out, we
go to court, and that's it. [laughter]
Okay? That's it. We're not running this.
We're not running away from you. I don't
know what you No, no, no, no. I'm
telling you, we're we are a law
enforcement's dream. We don't fight
back. We don't do anything. We go to
court and we go to jail.
>> We don't profile. Oh, we treat everybody
the same exact way. We don't know what
you're capable of.
>> No, no, no. You're wrong about that,
bro. I'm right about that. No, you're
wrong about that. You You're out here in
LA for You got to go back in New York or
Chicago or places like that. You'll see
a whole different atmosphere. And let me
tell you something, I agree with you
with the police. I agree. I am on the
side of the police in that regard. But
there are certain levels of law
enforcement that go for the names and go
for the promotion. There's no question
about it. You can't disagree. It's
happened.
>> Pause. You've been voted out by the
majority. Please return to your seat.
Thank you.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
[music]
>> No, I Nice to meet you.
>> I'm not going to talk about Hillary
Clinton and John Gotti. So,
>> um, unfortunately for us, I do think
that your arrest record is a direct
reflection of your work ethic. Uh, I
think that you can take one guy on the
street and you can say, "This guy made a
100 arrests this year." And from an
internal perspective, you say, "Man,
that dude shows up, he busts his ass and
works really hard." That sounds terrible
to the public that I'm out there
arresting x amount of people. I probably
look ruthless and unforgiving or
whatever you want to say. But if you
take the same guy on my squad who's made
five arrests this year, what do you
think they say about that guy?
>> He's lazy.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, he's sitting under a tree. If
you drive past that guy in the public,
you say, "This is what my tax dollars
are going for." So, I feel like we can't
win uh no matter what. But if not by the
arrest record, you know, you could judge
off other things, but I mean, what else
would you, how else would they, you
know,
>> you know, I I think the difference is
here because my experience is mostly on
the federal level.
>> And when you're dealing with organized
crime, it's a whole different ballgame.
It really is. It's it's it's a different
kind of street crime. Okay? And let me
tell you something. during the golden
years of of the mob from the late 40s
right through the mid 80s when the RICO
act went crazy and put everybody in
jail. Those were the golden years of the
mob. New York Times, New York Post,
Daily News, Long Island Press, News Day,
something about the mob every single
day. Again, Gotti, Fat Tony, Joe
Colombo, they were all bigger than life.
>> You mean [clears throat] to tell me that
people don't go after these guys, okay,
because they know it's a big feather in
their cap? It's human nature? Of course
they do. I'm not saying it happens on
every level. I'm certainly not saying it
happens on law. I would hope that you
make a lot of arrests for criminals out
there. It's sickening to me when I look
back and I see guys that were arrested
17, 18, 19 times and then come back out
on the street and murder somebody. It's
horrific. [clears throat]
I don't even I can't even comprehend it.
Okay, that's a different kind of crime.
But when you go on a bigger level, a
federal level, and they go after these
big politicians and they go after
organized crime guys and guys with big
names, of course they're going to get
promotions and of course that's in their
head. So what does that cause them to
do? In my world, it causes them to
stretch. Hey, I I got to get this guy.
This means a lot to me.
>> Okay. It's only normal. Do you I mean do
you not you keep referencing like the
big names and the cases and things that
you went through and respectfully.
>> Do you not see like I don't know more
body cameras and there's cameras
everywhere. Standards have changed,
methods have changed. Do you not think
all these things have changed for the
better? Not saying it's perfect. I see
the videos and things like you are
reverencing. I still see it. I
understand them. That'll be perfect. But
at the same time, do you still think
those things are happening like the way
that they used to at the level that they
used to?
>> Yes. You do.
>> Yeah. I I I unfortunately look I think
that a certain level of government was
corrupt during my time. I can't even
comprehend the level of corruption that
I see now. Not at your level, not at
police force. I'm not saying that at
all. Okay? I'm saying in the higher
levels. FBI. It's it's shameful what the
FBI has become in my opinion. They were
there were certain sectors of it that
weren't good during my time, but what I
see now
>> pause. You've been voted out by the
majority.
>> Thank you. Good. Thank you. Thank you.
>> How are you? Not bad yourself.
>> Good.
>> So, you've introduced yourself. I'll
introduce myself. So, I have worked
organized crime. I have investigated
very very bigname people north of the
border. Some probably your allies, some
probably your um your enemies or
whatnot. I take offense when you say
that organized crime enforcement
officers like myself on a federal level
get promotions because you know what I
got after investigating some very
highlevel people names that I'm not even
going to share. I got a pat on the back,
a destroyed relationship with my ex.
Hours upon hours of of reviewing search
warrants just to prepare for the case
that bleeds into my personal time. I
don't even have a personal life. I
didn't have a personal life for two
years and another case. So when you say
that oh yeah, everyone gets promoted or
everyone.
>> No, I didn't say that. Not everyone.
>> Okay.
>> I said it gives incentive to those
>> I never got an incentive. I did not know
I was going to get promoted nor did my
team members. I didn't even know if I
was going to get this guy to begin with.
>> Mhm. All I had was this idea of knowing
that, you know what, if I get the drugs,
I get the guns off the street, maybe 10,
15 kids get to live. I really didn't
care if that, of course, everyone wants
to get the bad guy, but sometimes that
doesn't happen. And you've admitted it.
Sometimes that doesn't happen. I'm not
going to I'm not going to destroy my
career doing something illegal when I
know I can get the drugs and the guns
off the street and save 15 people. So
when you say that people get promoted
off this, not true at all. What they do
get, what they do get is years and years
of of therapy and having to rebuild
their entire lives. That's why I left
organized crime because it destroyed my
life. I no longer do that because it
absolutely destroyed my life. So I never
got an I never got a promotion. I never
got this massive incentive. Um, all I
got was another case to work on.
>> Well, in part I agree with you. Joe
Piston, you know, uh, Donnie Brasco,
after everything that he did, you know,
I think they gave him a $500 check
afterwards and then he he he left the
FBI. Okay, but talk about a guy like
Andrew Weissman. Andrew Weissman
prosecutor, federal prosecutor who
framed people. And I got absolute proof.
I don't say this out of turn. framed
people, put people in jail innocently,
suborned perjury, worked with an FBI
agent that was involved in murder,
covered up crimes that go so deep you it
would make your hair stand on end. And
what does he get? He gets a promotion. A
promotion. A promotion. And his final
promotion was being the lead prosecutor
in the Mueller investigation against
Trump after he put so many people. He
was overturned nine to nothing by the
Supreme Court in a case that he did. And
he keeps getting promoted, promoted, and
promoted. and he gets all of these big
deals and he does. I mean, it h all I'm
saying is it happens. It happens more
than you might think. Unfortunately, it
didn't happen for you. But there are a
lot of prosecutors out there, especially
in uh Department of Justice prosecutors
that go after the big names and they get
promotions as a result. Even if they
lose the case, at times they get
promotions. But this guy, Andrew
Weissman, do me a favor, look him up.
Terrible guy. Put so many innocent
people in jail, destroyed their lives.
>> Right. But you're talking about a
lawyer. Okay. I believe the statement
was
>> Well, he's law he's he's a prosecutor.
>> Okay. I'm talking about cops.
>> I I agree with you with cops.
>> As a cop, I'm not going to bend the
rules. I'm not going to manufacture
crime. I'm not going to I'm not going to
put someone in a position where, as you
mentioned, fabricate or manufacture
crime. We don't we don't fabricate
crime, nor do we manufacture crime.
>> Ah, we we had that argument already,
>> right? [laughter] But but you brought it
back. I'm talking from my level from
working in organized crime. There's a
lot of checks.
>> You mean to tell me that you you you
you're saying to me that nobody in law
enforcement ever manufactured a crime by
putting a confidential informant in some
in front of somebody to create a crime
that never existed. That's manufacturing
the crime.
>> Sorry, you've been voted out by the
majority.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> How are you?
So with respect to your claim, you're
talking about focusing more on arrest
rather than safer streets, correct?
>> Many times, depending upon the
situation, yes,
>> of course. So with respect to the
audience, for the most part, they don't
care about the federal level. They care
about walking around the streets on
here.
>> You said you have daughters, correct?
>> Five.
>> Would you feel safe if they walked
around the streets here
>> in LA? No.
>> Yes, in LA.
>> No. [laughter]
No.
>> So then what to use a safer street or
how do you achieve a safer street? Well,
I think that um leadership has to give
law enforcement the tools and the
weapons that they need to keep the
streets safe. I think that's their
primary goal.
>> All right. Keep the streets safe.
>> Right. And so with respect to that
though, to get safer streets, you have
to eliminate the crime element. Correct.
>> Yes.
>> And the only way to do that really is to
arrest people because once you arrest
them
>> and if the court system actually did
their job, they'd be put in jail.
>> Yes. So just like you know if you
actually took it to trial you would have
been away for a long time. That's how
you achieve a safer street you know to
actually
>> wouldn't have been safe by putting me
away for a long time. I'm sorry.
[laughter]
>> I've been out for 30 some odd years now
and the streets have been pretty safe.
So it's okay. But
>> I would actually push back on that. I
actually think for at least temporarily
it was a little bit safer once you got
arrested because
>> it wasn't safer. I mean I was stealing
tax money. That's all I was doing.
But going back to your argument, I
think, you know, in order
>> Let's talk about somebody else,
[laughter]
>> John Gotti. Um, in order to achieve
safer streets, you have to eliminate the
criminal element. You have to arrest
criminals.
>> I agree with that. All I'm saying is
that there are times depending upon the
situation and who the subject is, the
alleged perpetrator that people will
stretch because they know it's a feather
in their cap, and they'll get
promotions. And I can document that. I
can tell you where it's happened,
>> right? But I mean, you know, if you do
arrest, let's say, you know, going to
the fed level, you arrest somebody who's
a big name, of course they're going to
get accolades for it's just like if a
high level executive, you know, lands
big contract, they're going to get a
bonus. I mean, that's
>> and that can give them more incentive
to, you know, not not so much the crime
they're committing, but the fact that
it's that person committing the crime.
>> Then do you feel like it's, you know,
obviously you mentioned, you know,
they're going to stretch things just to
get that accolade. Then do you feel like
humans in general are going to do
whatever it takes to get that accolade?
>> Some law enforcement,
>> but on law enforcement level, they're
not supposed to do that.
>> No. And I don't think they will just
because
>> Well, they will. They've done it. Um and
and that's an unfortunate part of our
law enforcement system. And I think, you
know, clarify, I think this is more on a
prosecutorial level. It's more it's more
political at that point. We're not
talking about, you know, a lot of the
look I I don't know what it is. I mean,
if you make a 100 arrests or you make 30
arrests, you know, what's the difference
to you guy? I don't know that, you know.
>> You've been voted out by the majority.
>> Thank you,
>> Mike. My pleasure meeting you.
>> Thank you. Okay, so a couple of things.
It is breaking the law, running a red
light, but you're saying that it's okay
for us to break the law. Did I get that
right?
>> Well, let me get clear on this. If you
have a suspect that has broken the law,
>> let's go John Gotti. Sorry to interrupt.
I'm chasing John Gotti. I'm an FBI
agent. I got like
>> Are you an FBI agent?
>> No, I'm not. But what I'm saying because
you keep saying so I just want to I want
to get something very clear. Sure. Okay,
let's get clear here. And words have
meanings.
>> You're saying at the federal level, hey,
you know what? If you arrest John Gotti
or some big name, uh, you're going to
get promoted, right? You're going to cut
corners. Uh, you're gonna stretch
whatever it is to do that. But hey, the
DUI guy, no. So, essentially, what
you're saying is that it's
[clears throat] self- serving on my
part.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. But is it self- serving on the DUI
driver? Yes or no?
>> If you arrest the DUI driver,
>> probably not.
>> Okay. So, that sounds a little
contradictory.
>> Not at all. You're making my point.
>> I'm I'm No. Well,
>> I'm making your point, but you're
contradicting what you're saying because
you're saying things at a 30,000 ft
level where you're
>> What's the difference? Still law
enforcement.
>> There's a big difference.
>> You still take an oath to do the same
thing, right? The law.
>> What I'm trying to tell you is that it's
not self- serving on either level. You
keep talking about levels. Is there
corruption? Yes. Is there self- serving
people who want to promote? Yes. But for
you to Well, that's not what you're
saying. No, it's not. Am I saying?
>> Where's the BS button?
>> Tell me what No, no, no. Wait. I'm going
to tell you.
>> Tell me exactly what I'm saying.
>> What you're saying, you're being a
little contradictory. You're saying,
"Hey, you know what? At the federal
level, if it's John Gotti or something
so big, then you know what? You're doing
it for self-s serving reasons. But for
the DUI guy, I'm not. I'm here to tell
you whether you're doing it for self-s
serving reasons or not. It doesn't
matter. And by the way, if I'm chasing
John Gotti, FBI, and we know we got
them. We got all the PC. We got
everything that we've been working for
five years. and I'm running a red light.
Guess what? I broke the law.
Me as a FBI agent, local, state,
>> so then so then a cop following you
while you're following while where you
as a police officer is going after
somebody that broke the law and you go
through the red light to catch him, a
cop behind you can pull you over and
give you a ticket.
>> No, wait a minute.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> So that they can.
>> Yes, they can. Yes.
>> Okay. I didn't know that. The other
gentleman said that you weren't
breaking.
>> Hold on a second. Words have meaning.
Which is it? We're saying
>> which is it. Did you Was he wrong? Let
me finish.
>> Was your Was your partner there or
whatever? Is not your part of
>> I'm not saying that. Was he wrong? Well,
he said that you it's it's not illegal
for a police officer to go run a red
light to catch a perpetrator.
>> That's what I'm saying. I can break.
Hold on.
>> Is it legal illegal?
>> Well, it's
>> Is it legal or illegal?
>> You can't run a red. You can't even when
you're even when you're uh pursuing a
perpetrator that just committed a crime.
>> Correct. It's No, what I'm saying is is
that wrong. Hold on a second.
>> Go talk to him. Talking about him.
>> Go ahead.
>> Just listen to my point.
>> Okay.
>> But who's wrong and who's right? Is he
wrong? He said it was okay to You're not
breaking the law when you run a red
light. That's what he said. Is he wrong
or right?
>> He is right because we do. Hold on a
second. Let me finish.
>> There are rules of the road that we're
immune by. I totally agree with that.
>> All right. So then it's illegal for you
to chasing God's gun.
>> But I broke the law.
>> But he said it was legal. You're allowed
to break the law. So then it's not
breaking the law.
>> So then I go to court and then you know
the I'm working undercover and I run a
red. And then all of a sudden the black
and white pulls me over and says, "Hey,
you ran a red. You were going after
John. You were undercover. They didn't
know who you were." Cop.
>> Okay. Well, this
>> when you go to court and you say, "I was
a cop and I was pursuing a perpetrator."
They're going to say, "Get out."
>> Let's keep in perspective. You're right.
I'm on a black and white and I'm running
the red. Okay. And I'm And you're
saying, "Yeah." Hey, you know what?
>> I can do that. I agree with you.
>> No, he said that. I didn't say that.
>> I Everybody here can agree with me.
That's not the point. I broke the law by
running the red.
>> All right. Can we get him over here
because he's mistaken?
>> No, he's not mistaken.
>> Well, one of you are.
>> I'm immune from the rules of the row
when I
>> Then you're not breaking the law.
>> Totally disagree. You're not You're
missing my point.
>> Well, what is your point?
>> I broke the law.
>> Well, not according to him. You just
said you're immune.
>> We're going back and forth.
>> You just said you're immune from
breaking the law. Immunity means you
didn't break the law. When you go to
court, they give you No, no, no, no, no.
You go to court and they give you
immunity for anything that you might
have committed. Correct. Okay. So, you
didn't you didn't you're okay then. So,
you're like when I go to court like 2
months later, but I'm saying I broke the
law right when it happened.
>> Not according to him.
>> Okay. Got that. [laughter]
>> Thank you.
My final surrounded claim is that paid
informants are rarely reliable.
>> How are you?
>> How many times did you actually discover
that informants were working against
you? And how do you actually think that
informants work from my side of the
table?
>> I've been to trial five times. I've been
through uh three separate trials with my
dad. I've never seen a paid informant
get on the stand, put his left hand on
the Bible, swear to tell the truth, and
then lie through his teeth. Every single
time.
>> Every single time.
>> Who worked the investigations against
you? FBI,
>> FBI, local police, um, Suffach County,
Nassau County, uh, Florida, same thing.
>> When you worked at federal level, there
was no cooperative information or
evidence that was ever submitted with
that informant.
>> No, I didn't say that. Well, you said
every.
>> Every that means all the time and all
the time. Every time.
>> That's correct.
>> Unless it wasn't every time.
>> No, it was every time. And I've never
seen them. Listen, you can mix the truth
with a lie,
>> but I've never seen them get on the
stand, left hand on the Bible, right
hand swear to tell the truth, and lie.
>> So, we're co-mingling lies with truth.
>> Sure.
>> So, it's not straight out lies. You're
saying that they they misrepresented or
they flat out lied.
>> I'm saying they lied. So, did you ever
have yourself on a recording, for
example, with an informant?
>> Oh, yeah. 83 times.
>> That memorialization of that recording,
was that truthful or was that a lie?
>> Well, they couldn't use the uh 83 times
that they had me on tape, they couldn't
use it to indict me.
>> Was that one case?
>> That was one case. Yes.
>> What about the other four cases?
>> Never on tape.
>> Never had a wire tap.
>> Had wire tap, but never able to use
anything against me.
>> For indictment or during trial?
>> For indictment. They were never able to
use those wires to implicate me in a
crime.
>> Did you understand now looking back on
it the federal rules for using
informants with an FBI agent?
>> The federal rule.
>> The federal rules for
>> Explain it to me.
>> I will explain it to you. So everything
we do with an informant has to be
cooperated in some fashion. We're not
just going to throw evidence based upon
pure and simple testimony of an
informant. If that's happening, then
you're dealing with an amateur.
>> Let me tell you something. You're
dealing with guys on the street who will
do many of them will do anything for
money.
>> And what you mean to tell me is that
when you're paying this informant,
you're not giving him incentive to lie.
Let me tell you, no, let me let me back
this up.
>> I was indicted uh for a a huge fraud
case in the gasoline business.
>> My partner, okay, was with me. We
created this scheme to defraud the
government.
>> He was a paid informant. They paid him
$2.5 million of stolen gas tax money to
be a witness against
>> Who did that case?
>> Feds. FBI.
>> FBI did the case. So that $2.5 million
was paid how was it? Through seizure
works on that.
>> They didn't seize any money as far as
they didn't seize any money for me.
>> Okay.
>> They paid him $2.5 million.
>> And you were not convicted on that case.
>> I I took a plea.
>> Yeah. Why did you take a plea?
>> Long story. because I took a plea
because I knew that my former life was
falling apart. The RICO act was
devastating to many people. I had just
beaten a RICO case brought on by Rudy
Giuliani
>> and I knew that the life was in trouble.
I had a 14 agency task force assigned to
bring me down and I knew that I wasn't
long for that life because I had such a
target. I was arrested 18 times and had
seven indictments.
>> After all these cases, let me ask you,
Michael, were you guilty of crimes?
Yeah, I was guilty of crimes. Yeah.
Okay.
>> So, what does that have to do with it?
>> Was I guilty of the crime? Excuse me.
Was I guilty of the crime that they
indicted me on
>> the one time that I took a plea? Yes.
The other five times? No. All right.
We're going into a different area here,
but let let's talk about the paid
informants.
>> In my experience, paid informance, and
I'm going to take this even pertains to
my brother. I saw my brother get on a
stand and testify against my father. My
brother was a paid informant and as I
sat there and watched him I know he
lied. If my own brother will lie against
his father, okay, which is a very
extreme situation. I am telling you,
okay, I know guys on the street, that's
where I grew up. I know guys, you give
them money, you give them incentive. And
listen, it's it's a bad system. It's a
bad system. I'm not saying you don't use
informants. I understand you have to use
informants, but to pay informants, I can
I can give you so many cases where guys
are doing time because of paid
informants because these guys get up
there and lie. They have incentive to
lie.
>> At your trial,
>> pause. You've been voted out by the
majority. Please return to your seat.
>> Thank you.
[music]
>> In my experience, paid informants are
reliable. And I say that in a sense of
everything we do in law enforcement,
we're we have to check and verify. So
when an informant comes to us, we're not
going and knocking down Frances's door
and taking him away. Right? There's a
there's a a structure and things we have
to follow in order to ensure that the
information not only is that that's
presented is accurate, but we also take
into account why is he coming forward
with this information. And you have to
understand, we don't get to pick
witnesses, right? you guys provide those
for us. You know, an honest man is not
going to come and say, "Hey, I'm a part
of this family and we're doing wrong and
I I I want to come forth." We're dealing
with people who either have been shunned
or voted out of the family or however
that works or or they've been they feel
like they deserve the promotion, didn't
get it. So, we understand the intention
that's coming in. However, the
information they're providing we have to
take into account and then a lot of
times that information checks out and
some things don't. And when they don't,
we have a system in place, i.e. courts
and laws and policies and and
regulations that kind of weeds that that
stuff out. Right? If I take a incomplete
and lazy case to court, it may get
thrown out. That not only puts a stain
on me, that puts a stain on my
department and everybody in this room
who's taken an oath to to protect and to
serve. Do you deal with organized crime?
>> I not where I'm at now. Paid informants
I've dealt with on the street level to
get local neighborhood guys and people
who come from across states. That's
where my limit lies. But that being
said, in my experience, it's worked out.
>> All right. Well, let me tell you this.
You know, you you just laid out the way
it's supposed to be. You go back to New
York and you deal with the feds and
organized crime, you're in a whole
different world. Okay? These paid
informants don't come to you. Normally
they get in trouble and they get put in
a room and they said you're facing life
in prison on a racketeering act or you
want to sit down and talk with us. We'll
give you money. We'll put you in the
witness protection program. Help us out.
See what happened in my life. I'll tell
you very simple. The fear of retaliation
from our own people from the boss. You
screw up, you're going to get killed.
You're going to get in trouble. Well,
that fear was transferred to the
government when the RICO act came out
because now guys are going away for life
and they're getting whatever asset, if
they had any assets taken away. So now
you stick him in a room and you say,
"Hey, you're going to cooperate with us.
You're going to wire yourself up. You're
going to do what you got to do. We'll
pay you money because you don't have to
worry about the guy you're talking
about. We're putting him away for life."
When you put that incentive in front of
a paid informant, trust me, they're
going to go along with you and they'll
get on the stand and they'll lie and
they'll do whatever they have to do. And
I will say this, I can tell you straight
out that the government knows that many
of these informants are lying and they
don't care. As long as they win their
case, they don't care. Now, I'm not I'm
not saying that's you.
>> No, I'll have to disagree.
>> This is my experience. I
>> I'll have to I can't negate your
experience, but
>> you can disagree, but I'm telling you,
I've been through it.
>> The bad apple doesn't define a bad
orchard. Okay. So, how are these
informants getting in the rooms? Again,
we don't get
>> trouble,
>> but we're not making people get in
trouble. These informants are putting
themselves in positions. Absolutely.
>> And and we're just providing
>> we're providing the the avenue to be
able to now be a part of that situation.
Right. is the best way to get and you
can understand this. The best way to get
into that life is we need someone on the
inside to bring us in.
>> I understand that. But the point is, is
paying these guys giving them incentive
to lie? And it absolutely is. There's no
question about it.
>> It can. But given that checks and
balances that the government has, the
laws, if if they are being paid to lie,
our case gets thrown out if that's
simply what's coming on. It doesn't
happen.
>> Absolutely. You said it yourself. No, it
happened in your case. They paid to They
got paid. They lied and someone probably
didn't present it to the best of their
>> You want me to tell you about the other
hundred guys that are doing time because
of that? In my particular case, you
know, they were weak cases. I'm going to
be honest with you. Okay. But you want
me to tell you about the hundreds of
other guys that are in jail because of
lying paid informants.
>> So they there was no reason to make this
up.
>> There was no merit that
>> I didn't say [clears throat] there was
no merit. I said they're lying paid
informants. Can I ask you a question?
>> Absolutely. If these are if these are
great witnesses and they're there to
tell the truth and just really why do
you have to pay them at all?
>> I'm not saying they're great witnesses.
I'm saying
>> why do you have to pay them at all? Why
should they get paid if they're telling
the truth and helping law enforcement?
>> Because you guys operate with money. You
weaponize it. We use the same tactic
because that's what how people respond
sometimes.
>> You you don't have
>> and I've used witnesses that don't get
paid. I've used witnesses that have get
paid.
>> Well, then that's good. They don't have
that incentive at least from being paid.
But let me tell you something. In in the
mob life, we're not paying these guys.
They're paying they're making their own
money and they're pay nobody hands
anybody anything in that life. You got
to be your own person.
>> But money money rules money rules of
life, right? Or you wouldn't be doing
it. That the incentive is money. You
weaponize money. Not you, but it's
weaponized and it's an incentive for
them, right? Why do that? Because
they're getting something in return.
There's a something that's been an
opportunity provided to them.
>> But why do you have to pay them at all?
>> We don't have to. That's not the case
for you.
>> I I can't speak on why they were paid in
your case.
>> I know I but I can. They were paid to
they were paid because they they were
given incentive to become witnesses.
They pay them and that incentive makes
them lie. Trust me on that.
>> But let's look at let's look at the the
the bigger picture, right? Informants
have gone a long way to help us with
organized crime.
>> I agree with inform the question is why
do you have to pay them? Tom, they got
to understand, oh, you know, I want to
clear my conscience. So, I want to do
the right thing. Yeah, right. You're
getting paid. You're not only getting
paid, but you're going to do less time.
You're going to cooperate with us. We'll
put your family in a witness protection
program. We'll give you money. Anything
that you want, don't worry about it. And
you tell me that's not incentive to lie
when these guys are facing big time.
>> That's an incentive for a whole
different thing.
>> You've been voted out by the majority.
Please return to your seat.
>> Thanks a lot. Thank you.
>> How we doing today? We're good.
>> All right. From New York, right?
>> Yeah.
>> So, we both know. Okay. I dealt with
Peyton formers before um throughout my
career. My thing is this. Both you and I
know. You know, it's like Darwinism.
It's survival of the fittest. You know,
who can survive in that in that world,
right? Both you and I know a CI is a CI
is a CI is a CI. First thing I did when
I dealt with a CI was hand them a gift,
okay? to let them know that my life's on
the line, your life's on the line. We're
both built into this together. But you
already said it. You, you know, I don't
think it's the paid part that's the
issue. The issue I think what you're
getting at is the system.
The system itself and how the system
operates. Paid informants. Yeah. You
know what? It all comes down to a
person's personal freedom. If we're in
the same family and we're dealing with
the same issues, you know, you're no
better than I am. I'm no better than
your you are. You know what? I want my I
want I want my freedom. I want to be
able to enjoy my life if I'm going to
get paid in my freedom and I'm going to
tell the truth. You know what? What's
What's wrong with that incentive?
>> If you're going to tell the truth, but
it's the money that gives them incentive
to lie. Also, you look, there's two
things that they want. They want money
and they want their freedom. I've seen
so many guys get understand, oh, I
changed my life and I'm okay and you
know, the mob was bad to me and all of
this. Listen, we get in there, we take
an oath. We take an oath. We know
exactly the life you chose.
>> We we exa we know exactly what the
penalties are. Look, I walked away from
that life. I had a contract on my life.
They wanted to kill me, but I understood
I violated my oath by walking away and
talking about it. I can't get mad at
them. I did what I said I wasn't going
to do. I violated my oath. So, I
understand that. But some of these
witness get on say I'm a good person now
and they treated me wrong and they
didn't do this and they're going to get
up and they're going to lie and they're
going to do whatever the heck they have
to do to save themselves and they're
going to keep it going as long as they
could. They don't become choir boys when
they become witnesses. They're the same
guys that were on the street lying and
stealing and doing all of that. Now
they're supposed to be good guys.
Nonsense. There are a lot of good people
in government, but there are a lot of
people that'll stretch the truth to get
what the heck they want, and they'll use
witnesses and they'll pay him and
they'll do whatever they need to do.
I've witnessed it my whole life. My
father did 50 years on a crime he didn't
commit. I'll take it to my grave. Every
one of the informants lied. We gave him
lie detector tests afterwards, okay?
Prove they lied at the trial. They were
paid informants. They're all a bunch of
junkies. We could never get the
conviction overturn. My dad did 40 on
that 50 for a crime he didn't commit.
Was he a mob guy? Yeah. Did he do other
things? Yeah. But get him for what he
did.
>> Get the guy for what he did.
>> Pause. We're out of time on this claim.
Thank you.
>> Thank you, man. Hey, thanks a lot.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Um,
>> hey,
>> you have a client?
>> I sure do.
>> Sure.
>> Again,
>> I chose Heather for the final debate
because I think she held her own in the
discussion that we had.
>> You didn't win, but you held your own.
>> I mean, that's debatable, right?
>> Yes.
>> Just like everything today. [laughter]
My surrounded claim is that the mafia
culture glorifies or promotes men to be
successful only through fear and
intimidation.
>> Okay. So, what you're saying is that men
that were involved in the mafia uh are
really not smart. Uh they really don't
know anything but fear and that's how
they uh earn money. That's how they
become successful within that life. If
you take the element of fear away, we're
all a bunch of dummies.
>> That's absolutely not what I said.
>> Okay.
>> What I said is that your power is
legitimized through intimidation and
fear. And that if you took those away,
you wouldn't actually have the so-called
respect that you think that you have,
right? We earlier you were talking about
promotions and all these things. The
mafia does the same thing. I mean, how
do you think John Gotti got promoted?
Right? He killed Castellano,
>> right? So, it's all about the actions
that you're taking to get there. It's
through fear and intimidation. I'm not
saying that you're not smart and no no
part of my statement said that any of
you were dumb at all. I just think I and
I'm probably going to have to hear about
this if someone takes this the wrong
way. Hitler, right? The way he led was
fear, intimidation, pulling people in
and then they didn't know if they were
coming in to meet him, whether or not
they were going to get killed or whether
or not they were going to get like a pat
on the back. So, what I'm saying is that
it's not about servant leadership when
it comes to the mafia. It's not about
the leadership components that we as law
enforcement should be pushing for right
now, which is that human aspect, uh the
the humility behind leadership. It's
it's about fear and intimidation when it
comes to the mafia.
>> Don't you think that fear plays an
element in almost any walk of life? If
you're in government and you make a
mistake, well, the fear is that you can
lose your job. If you're in corporate
America, you make a mistake, the fear is
you can lose your job. Now, when you get
to the mob, well, it's a little bit more
serious because the consequences are
more severe because there is this big
aura about the mafia that you don't do
the right thing, you're going to get
killed. Okay? Is that always so? Of
course not. It's not the case at all.
There are plenty of people in that life
that never had to resort to fear or an
intimidation to get their way. Never.
So, even though it's an element of that
life, I think it's very wrong to say
that if it wasn't for the element of
fear, there wouldn't be success in that
life. But as far as that's concerned, if
you were just if you didn't have the
fear and you didn't have that
intimidation, how do you keep your power
within the mafia?
>> Well, when you say keep your power
within that life,
>> I mean, you guys run a hierarchy just
like we do.
>> Yeah. Well, it's very simple because we
all take an oath and we hold each other
to a high standard. And that oath is
that we realize that there are certain
consequences we can pay if we violate
the oath. And so, the fear is a little
bit more intense in that life because we
agree to it. But um it's not always fear
that makes people rise in the ranks.
There's a guy by the name of Roy Deo,
okay? He was a serial killer. Roy Deo
would have been a serial killer whether
he was in the mafia or not. Mafia just
gave him easier access, let's say. Okay?
And there was a certain amount of fear
about that guy because he was a madman.
But that didn't help him rise in the
ranks. He ended up getting killed as a
result of that, you know. So sometimes
when people fear you, it could work
against you. In his case, it did. Now,
I'm going to be honest with you. You
know, I stayed in line because I
realized if I made a mistake, I could
pay for it in a in a severe way. So, it
does keep us in line in a certain way.
Like I say, the consequences are more
severe. But fear is an element of almost
every organization or every life.
>> Fear is an internal element, but it can
also be an external element as far as
leadership is concerned. And when it
comes to the hierarchy and keeping that
and making sure there aren't
corroborating witnesses or confidential
informants that come through or people
that turn around and they take a plea
deal and then they have a contract put
on their head. That's that fear
component that we don't utilize in law
enforce shouldn't use in law
enforcement.
>> Mhm.
>> When you say that shouldn't use in law
enforcement. So for you that fear
component was very real. That
intimidation of you leaving the life was
there was it not?
>> But I left.
>> You did. And for how long were you in
fear of your life?
Well, let's put it this way. I knew that
there could be consequences that I could
face, but I also knew the life very
well. So, I knew what I had to do to
protect myself. So, I didn't live in
fear. I honestly didn't. I didn't sell
my former associates short. I knew what
they were capable of, but I also felt
that I can, you know, do my best to
avoid that. But I think what you're
saying is that's one of the main reasons
why we succeed in that life because of
fear. And I disagree with that.
>> Why do you disagree with it though?
>> Because it's not true. But you just said
it was you just said that there was
fear. Just because you didn't have fear,
fear and intimidation was used in order
to keep you in line because if you
walked in a room, you might not walk out
>> if you did something wrong.
>> But
>> if you violated the oath, yes. But in
order to succeed in that life, and
you're not violating the oath, it wasn't
fear that allowed me to succeed in that
life. It was having an understanding of
the life, knowing how to use that life
to benefit me in business and where I
had my success. So fear didn't cause me
to be a good mob guy.
>> But do you think the head boss used fear
and intimidation more than anything
else?
>> He didn't use it against me. I just knew
that it was there.
>> I didn't mean just against you. I meant
the mafia culture as a whole.
>> Yes, it's it's an element of fear in
that life like there is in other lives
except that the consequences are more
severe. But what I'm saying is fear
doesn't cause you to be a success in
that life. It's to me it's understanding
the life and knowing how to use it to
benefit you in whatever it is you're
trying to do. But I will tell you this,
you know, when I walked into a room
sometimes to negotiate with somebody,
well, that aura was there. I didn't have
to say anything. They knew who I was.
They knew what I represented. So maybe
the fear was from the other side. You
know, I better watch what I say here.
Stuff like that. Yeah. So there's a bit
of an intimidation factor when you
walked into the room because of your
reputation, the way you held yourself.
>> So fear and intimidation are the basis
of some of the leadership and the
culture that is within the mafia.
>> It's it's not the primary driving force,
but yes, it is an element and some
people do use that. Yes,
>> that's my claim. Sounds like you agree
with me.
>> Well, I agree in part. [laughter]
>> I'll take that. I agree in part. I agree
in part. I mean, listen, it, you know,
intimidation is something and and you
said it about the fear, right? You can
be intimidating, but it's a you can
intimidate others, it doesn't mean
you're intimidating. It's that it's that
aura that you walk into the room with.
>> Listen, the smart bosses in that life,
they knew they knew that violence and
fear was destructive.
>> You know, let me let me tell you
something. I had a discussion with uh
with Chaz Palter. He saw he wrote the
movie Bronxale. He's a good friend of
mine. And in the movie Bronx Tale, he's
asked the question by Little Collogio.
Is it better to be feared or loved? And
he said, "It's better to be feared in my
position." And I had that discussion
with Chaz afterwards. I said, "Chaz,
you're not a member of the mob, but you
were around guys. What do you think?" He
said, "Oh, Michael, it's better to be
feared." I said, "You're wrong." He
says, "Why?" I said, "I'll tell you
why." I said, "When the government came
out with the racketeering act and people
knew that they can go away forever, lose
all their assets and everything else."
Well, the fear of the mob, okay, was
transferred to the fear of the
government because the government now
held all the power. And so, so many guys
became informants. Many guys became
informants because of that. So, fear is
not a great element. It's really not.
It's more destructive than anything
else. So, it can hold you in line for a
for a part until it gets unless it gets
transferred somewhere else. But love,
you're not going to hurt somebody you
love.
>> I've seen a lot of people hurt people
that they love. Well, I mean, you know,
you know what I mean. Come on. Not to a
level where you All right, I surrender
[laughter] on that one. I surrender. You
got me on that one. I surrender. Yeah. I
mean, okay. But you know what I mean.
Not to a level where you're going to
want to destroy them. I think anyway. I
hope not.
>> Yeah. I mean, I think that our our jobs,
I'll put it that way. Um our lifestyles
mimic each other so much.
>> Oh, absolutely.
>> Just on different perspectives, right?
When we walk into a room on a call, we
have a level of fear and we go anyway.
The same is true.
>> You know what? I should have said that.
You're [laughter] absolutely right. Who
doesn't get scared when they see a
police officer most of the time? Yeah.
>> So, look at the element of fear that you
use.
>> But is that something that we use on
purpose or is that a
>> It's the aura. It's there. It's the
uniform. You're the police. You can
arrest me. You can lock me up. You can
hurt me. You can shoot me. So, that
culture that's been created,
>> huh?
>> It's that culture that's been created.
You talked about the glory years or the
golden years of the mafia and being on
every single newspaper headline. Well,
who do you think's there now?
>> I know it's a shame. I don't agree with
that. I I disagree with that. But you
know what? People should have a certain
level of fear of law enforcement. That's
what keeps them in line. It keeps the
criminals in line. In our life, to a
degree, it kept us in line. So, what's
the difference?
>> The difference to in my opinion, right,
is I and I believe that I was very lucky
in where I grew up. I didn't have a fear
of police. They were there as the
heroes. They were the ones that came to
save the day. When I walk into a room
and somebody goes, "Oh, you better
behave. I'm going to have that police
officer um take you away." Like, that's
not something I'm instilling in someone.
That's the parent instilling that fear
in their child about who we are. And I
think the same has been said about your
reputation and who the mafia is, right?
After sitting here and hearing you all
day, like I feel like you and I could be
best friends because, [laughter] right,
but I'm not scared of you. I'm not there
there isn't a fear element on my end
when it comes to you. But I do believe
that your the the leadership style
within the culture of the mafia is
something based on fear and
intimidation. I don't believe those are
the only elements, but I do believe
historically that's where it came from.
>> There's an element of fear in almost
every walk of life.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and again, it's it's accentuated in
the mob life. I I will agree with that.
But I what I disagree is it's that fear
that made the life successful. I just
there's a lot of guys in that life that
if they have chose to go in the
legitimate world, they would have been
brilliant and very successful. Trust me,
you know, no other organization has
thrived like we had during that and I'm
not bragging and I'm not glorifying. I'm
just telling the truth, you know, under
some very serious conditions. And the
ones that succeeded, they did it because
of their brains and their determination.
>> Pause. We're out of time. Thank you so
much.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Great. That's a great
question, by the way. Thank you.
[applause]
Thank you.
>> You know, normally if I'm surrounded by
20 law enforcement agents, I'm under
arrest. So, it was nice to be able to
sit and debate with them. You know, it
was it was a good experience.
>> I think Michael got a lot of things
wrong. [music] I think that he didn't
really understand that uh at every level
of law enforcement. [music] I don't care
what agency you work for, there are
standards, procedures, and elements that
we have to follow before you even build
a case. He did give us immediate
respect, which I thought was was
interesting because I I didn't expect
that walking in here. I thought it was
really going to be a little bit more
adversarial. I
>> I grew quite frustrated at times. He
claims that agents suborn perjury
routinely uh in my 23 years. I never saw
any indication of that.
>> You know, for him to sit there and say
that there isn't uh that the FBI today
and that there isn't corruption among
the FBI, I think that was that was poor
on his part. The culture of the
organization is very much rule oriented,
very much get approval and document
whatever you do.
>> He may be an agent with ethics and
integrity, [music] but he has to know
that a lot of people in his department
now, especially over the last four
years, didn't act that way.
>> Well, of course, if if someone is
successful in their field, that will
advance their career. That's not in
[music] and of itself proof of
corruption.
>> There's no glamour in working organized
crime. That's something that I don't
think Michael understands.
>> I think I swayed him and everything, so
he ended up [laughter] agreeing with me
pretty well. I do think that fear and
intimidation helps you rise through the
ranks of the [music] mafia.
>> Arresting people that were in the mafia
does not make the street safer. Listen,
our neighborhoods were the safest
neighborhoods around. There was no
street crime going on unless we were
doing it and we weren't doing it like
that. We didn't hurt people. We help
people in our community in our
neighborhoods. The leaders in today's
world, they they rule by fear and and it
should never be like that. And it goes
both ways in both the mafia and in uh
policing.
>> You know, a lot of people think, you
know, when we take that oath, it's an
oath of silence. It's not an oath to
lie, steal, kill, murder. That's not the
oath. Do things like that happen? Yes,
but that's not the oath that we take.
So, we didn't go around creating street
crimes all over the place. That's not
what we were involved in. We were a bit
more sophisticated than